Serge Durand

Full stack Django and MERN developer

+237 651209832

- https://serge.codes https://linkedin.com/in/ sergedurand205
- Yaoundé, Cameroon

EXPERIENCE

Django developer

URL Shortener - tinyy.ink

10/2022 - 11/2022

- Developed a web app used to convert long links to shorter ones.
- Used CAPTCHA to enhance security by preventing bots and automated requests.
- · QR code generation of links

Lead MERN developer

Thesis Follow up at UY1 - edc-stg.online

06/2022 - 08/2022

- Led a team of 5 developers into developing a platform to follow up the thesis of postgraduate students.
- Implemented secure and reliable API for frontend-backend communication while improving speed of CORS requests by more than 40%.
- Used Agile methodology and Scrum techniques to speed up the development process by more than a week.

Reactjs Developer

Copy-paste Frontend - amicopy.vercel.app

05/2022 - 05/2022

 Created template home, auth and pricing pages for a "copy-paste" website. i.e website for copying and pasting content among multiple devices.

Django & Wordpress developer

TechniqConsulting - techniqconsulting.com

12/2021 - 03/2022

- Internship at an IT consultancy and software development company.
- Using WordPress instead of coding from scratch where necessary helped to save time of projects 10 fold.
- Increased number of clients and user experience thanks to ability to speak both English and French.

Django developer

CS Portal - camerschools.site

06/2021 - 10/2021

 Developed a platform that offers numerous services such as buying, selling and requesting for items, publishing lost and found items, asking questions and discussing on various topics.

SUMMARY

I'm a full stack Django and Javascript(MERN stack) developer with over 2 years of experience. Thanks to my keen attention to detail and desire to always learn from collaborators, I get better after every project and always deliver before time.

SKILLS

Django

MERN Stack

SQL/NoSQL

TypeScript

Azure

DevOps

Docker

LANGUAGES

English Native
French Native

EDUCATION

Computer Science

University of Yaounde 1 2022

Bachelor's degree

 Developed a platform for the university to follow up the evolution of thesis projects of postgraduate students.